The first step of web scraping is getting the web page's data,
أول خطوة في استخلاص مواقع الويب هي استخراج البيانات من صفحات الويب،
which is stored in a format called,
المُخزنة بصيغة تسمى
HTML, HyperText Markup Language.
HTML، لغة ترميز النص الفائق.
One way of getting the HTML is by saving it to your computer manually,
إحدى الطرق للحصول على HTML هي حفظها يدويًا على جهاز الكمبيوتر،
going to your web page,
والذهاب إلى صفحة الويب،
then to your browser's menu,
ثم إلى قائمة المتصفح،
and clicking save or hitting command or control
والضغط على save أو الضغط على command أو Ctrl+S
S. But that's not the best way to do it for data analysis.
لكن ليست هذه هي الطريقة الأفضل لتحليل البيانات.
There are two better ways,
هناك طريقتين أفضل،
and they're both done programmatically,
والاثنان يعملان بطريقة برمجية،
which is best for scalability and reproducibility,
وهما أفضل في القابلية للتوسع والتكرار،
which is key in this case.
وهو شيء مهم في هذه الحالة.
Because we have 100 HTML files to access,
لأن لدينا 100 ملف HTML لنصل إليهم،
and multiple people, i.e.,
وأشخاص عديدة، على سبيل المثال،
every student that takes this class is going to access them.
سيكون لكل شخص يحضر هذا الدرس صلاحية الوصول إليهم.
Okay, so the first is actually downloading
لذا، يقوم الأول بتنزيل ملف
the HTML file programmatically to your computer.
HTML بطريقة برمجية إلى جهازك.
Here's all the code you need.
هذا هو الكود الذي تحتاجه.
You'll learn how this code works under the hood later in the lesson,
ستتعلم كيف يعمل هذا الكود في الخلفية لاحقًا في الدرس،
when you download files from the internet programmatically.
عند تنزيل الملفات من الإنترنت بطريقة برمجية.
This is just the code to download one file.
هذا هو الكود لتنزيل ملف واحد.
To download all 100 files,
ولتنزيل 100 ملف،
we just need to put this code in a loop.
نحتاج لوضع هذا الكود في تكرار حلقي.
The second programmatic way to access
الطريقة البرمجية الثانية للوصول
HTML data is done by not saving a file to your computer at all,
لبيانات HTML لا تستوجب حفظ الملف على جهازك إطلاقًا،
and simply working with the response content live in your computer's memory.
وتعمل ببساطة على محتوى الاستجابة الموجود في ذاكرة الكمبيوتر.
You can use the BeautifulSoup HTML parser
يمكنك استخدام محلل BeautifulSoup HTML
to help you work with the response content directly.
لمساعدتك على التعامل مع محتوى الاستجابة مباشرةً.
You're going to dive into this BeautifulSoup library shortly.
ستدخل إلى مكتبة BeautifulSoup مباشرةً.